<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://vsecm.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://vsecm.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-12-01T22:22:30-08:00</updated><id>https://vsecm.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">VMware Secrets Manager</title><subtitle>VMware Secrets Manager for Cloud-Native Apps is a cloud-native secure store  for secrets management. It provides a minimal and intuitive API, ensuring  practical security without compromising user experience.
Endorsed by industry experts, VMware Secrets Manager is a ground-up re-imagination  of secrets management, leveraging SPIRE for authentication and providing a  cloud-native way to manage secrets end-to-end.
VMware Secrets Manager is resilient and secure by default, storing sensitive  data in memory and encrypting any data saved to disk.
With VMware Secrets Manager, you can rest assured that your sensitive data is  always secure and protected.
</subtitle><author><name>Volkan Özçelik and Contributors</name></author><entry><title type="html">Keep Your Secrets… Secret</title><link href="https://vsecm.com/blog/keep-your-secrets/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keep Your Secrets… Secret" /><published>2023-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://vsecm.com/blog/keep-your-secrets</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://vsecm.com/blog/keep-your-secrets/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introducing-vmware-secrets-manager">Introducing VMware Secrets Manager</h2>

<p><img src="/assets/VSecM-1.png" alt="Welcome to the future of secrets management. (image generated by Midjourney)" /></p>

<p>In the ever-evolving landscape of cloud-native applications, secrets management
is critical to ensuring sensitive information’s security and integrity. While
several solutions are available, the recent shift in Hashicorp’s licensing towards
a Business Source License (<em>BSL</em>) has raised concerns and sparked discussions
within the community.</p>

<p>As the lead architect of <a href="https://vsecm.com/"><strong>VMware Secrets Manager</strong> (<strong><em>VSecM</em></strong>)</a>,
I’d like to take this opportunity to introduce our solution, which offers a robust,
flexible, and <strong>permissive</strong> alternative to Hashicorp’s Vault.</p>

<blockquote class="block-tip">
  <p><strong>⭐️ Star Us on GitHub ⭐️</strong></p>

  <p>If you find value in our approach and want to help others discover this outstanding
technology, <strong><a href="https://github.com/vmware-tanzu/secrets-manager">star our GitHub repository</a></strong>.
Your support helps increase visibility and encourages more collaboration and
innovation within the community.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="a-new-licensing-landscape">A New Licensing Landscape</h2>

<p>Hashicorp’s decision to adopt a Business Source License has been viewed by some
as a restrictive move. The BSL, unlike open-source licenses, imposes certain
limitations and conditions that may not align with the needs and values of all
organizations and developers.</p>

<p>In contrast, VMware Secrets Manager is licensed under the BSD 2-Clause License,
a permissive open-source license that encourages collaboration, innovation,
and freedom of use.</p>

<h2 id="vmware-secrets-manager-a-closer-look">VMware Secrets Manager: A Closer Look</h2>

<p><strong>VSecM</strong> is designed with modern developers and DevOps professionals in mind.
Here’s why it stands out:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Ease of Use</strong>: With a <a href="https://vsecm.com/docs/quickstart/"><strong>Quickstart Guide</strong></a>,
intuitive <a href="https://vsecm.com/docs/cli/?ref=zerotohero.dev"><strong>CLI</strong></a>, and
developer-friendly <a href="https://vsecm.com/docs/sdk/"><strong>SDK</strong></a>, <strong>VSecM</strong>
simplifies secrets management without compromising security.</li>
  <li><strong>Kubernetes Is a First-Class Citizen</strong>: <strong>VSecM</strong> seamlessly integrates with
Kubernetes, leveraging <a href="https://spiffe.io/docs/latest/spire-about/"><strong>SPIRE</strong></a>
for authentication and offering flexible secret storage and transformation options.</li>
  <li><strong>Community Engagement</strong>: We believe in open collaboration and community-driven
development. Our <a href="https://vsecm.com/docs/contributing/"><strong>Contributing Guide</strong></a>
invites developers to get involved, ask questions, and contribute to the project.</li>
  <li><strong>Secure by Default</strong>: <strong>VSecM</strong> offers advanced security features, including
encryption, manual master secret setting, and integration with various backing
stores.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="join-the-future-of-secrets-management">Join the Future of Secrets Management</h2>

<p><strong>VMware Secrets Manager</strong> is more than just a tool; it’s a community-driven project
that aims to redefine secrets management in a cloud-native world. We invite you to
explore <strong>VSecM</strong>, contribute to its growth, and join us in shaping the future of
secure and resilient applications.</p>

<p>Whether you’re a developer looking to contribute or an organization seeking a
flexible and secure solution for secrets management, <strong>VSecM</strong> offers a welcoming
and innovative platform.</p>

<h3 id="this-is-just-the-beginning-a-vision-for-the-future">This is Just the Beginning: A Vision for the Future</h3>

<p>At <strong>VMware Secrets Manager</strong>, we believe in continuous innovation and growth.
Our <a href="https://vsecm.com/docs/roadmap"><strong>roadmap</strong></a> is a testament to our commitment
to delivering cutting-edge solutions that meet the evolving needs of the cloud-native
community.</p>

<p>Here’s a glimpse of what’s on the horizon:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Stability and Usability Enhancements</strong>: Upcoming releases focus on improving
stability, documentation, build automation, and overall user experience.</li>
  <li><strong>Innovative Features</strong>: From Secretless VSecM to machine-readable logs,
performance improvements, and large-scale secret ingestion, we’re pushing the
boundaries of what’s possible in secrets management.</li>
  <li><strong>Integration and Compatibility</strong>: Future iterations include integration with
AWS KMS, Azure Key Vault, Google Cloud KMS, and even HashiCorp Vault, expanding
the reach and compatibility of VSecM.</li>
  <li><strong>Community Development and Collaboration</strong>: We are investing in community
development efforts, multi-cluster secret federation, and creating abstractions
to make cloud integrations easier.</li>
</ul>

<p>Our roadmap is not just a plan; it’s a promise to our users and contributors that
we have a lot planned for the future of <strong>VMware Secrets Manager</strong>.</p>

<p>We’re excited about the journey ahead and invite you to be a part of it.</p>

<blockquote class="block-tip">
  <p><strong>⭐️ Star Us on GitHub ⭐️</strong></p>

  <p>If you find value in our approach and want to help others discover this
outstanding technology, <strong><a href="https://github.com/vmware-tanzu/secrets-manager">star our GitHub repository</a></strong>.
Your support helps increase visibility and encourages more collaboration and
innovation within the community.</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="help-us-shape-the-future">Help Us Shape the Future</h3>

<p><a href="https://vsecm.com/"><strong>Start your journey with VMware Secrets Manager today</strong></a>
and unlock the potential of cloud-native secrets management.</p>]]></content><author><name>Volkan Özçelik</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the ever-evolving landscape of cloud-native applications, secrets management is critical to ensuring sensitive information’s security and integrity. While several solutions are available, the recent shift in Hashicorp’s licensing towards a Business Source License (BSL) has raised concerns and sparked discussions within the community.]]></summary></entry></feed>